<Guide id="install_liveries" name="How to Install Vehicle Liveries">
  <Author>Zylas</Author>

  <Page id="home">
    <Title><![CDATA[How to Install Vehicle Liveries]]></Title>
    <Description><![CDATA[
    This guide will allow you to replace your vehicle's liveries, all without prior modding experience required. 

    To start, you will need OpenIV, a vehicle you wish to replace the liveries of, and the texture you wish to add to the vehicle. 
    
    To make sure the vehicle livery you wish to install will fit, check the vehicle author's description on the LCPDFR website and navigate to the "Credits" tab. You should see a list of the vehicle bases used on the pack. Make sure the author of the base corresponds with the vehicle livery's author, which will typically be in the description or credits of the creator's file.
    ]]></Description>
    <Buttons>
      <Button type="interactive" targetPage="install"><![CDATA[Installation Guide]]></Button>
      <Button type="interactive" targetPage="troubleshooting"><![CDATA[Troubleshooting]]></Button>
      <Button type="interactive" targetPage="faq"><![CDATA[Frequently Asked Questions]]></Button>
    </Buttons>
  </Page>

  <Page id="install">
    <Title><![CDATA[How to Install Vehicle Liveries]]></Title>
    <Description><![CDATA[
    Note: Your pathway may vary slightly if you are using an add-on vehicle. This guide is intended for replacement vehicles.

        1. Navigate to the vehicle file, for replacement vehicles, this is at `GTAV/mods/update/x64/dlcpacks/patch2025_01/dlc.rpf/x64/levels/gta5/vehicles.rpf/`
        2. Locate the texture file (.YTD file) of the vehicle you wish to replace (ex `police2.ytd`).
        3. Right-click the file and click edit.
        4. Locate the texture file inside the YTD. As the name varies depending on the vehicle, some good names to search for are "livery" and "sign".
        5. Right-click the box and click "replace". Locate the PNG or DDS file of the livery you wish to use.
        6. Import the file and save your changes.
        7. If there is a secondary texture file (ex `police2_hi.ytd`) repeat steps 3-6. However, they may not always be a "livery" or "sign" texture in this secondary file. It will never be named differently.
        8. Locate the model file (.YFT file) 

    To view your new liveries in-game, spawn your vehicle and check the "livery" menu option under vehicle options.
    ]]></Description>
  </Page>

  <Page id="troubleshooting">
    <Title><![CDATA[Troubleshooting]]></Title>
    <Description><![CDATA[
    ]]></Description>
    <Fields>
      <Field name="Can I replace or add 'reflective' textures to my car?" inline="true"><![CDATA[
In order for a vehicle to have a reflective texture, it **must** be added by the vehicle's author. Simply adding a reflective texture a texture developer made will not automatically make the vehicle reflective. Second, the author must provide a texture without a background to it to make it appropriately reflective. Once done, you will need to follow the same instructions again, but this time search for "ref" or "reflective"
      ]]></Field>
    </Fields>
  </Page>

</Guide>
